Inventory of the California Department of Industrial Relations. Division of Statistics and Research Records, 1913 - 1984
Labor Archives and Research Center
- WOMEN WORKERS--SAN FRANCISCO--COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN--MINUTES, 1976 (Box 34/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1940 - 1941 (Box-folder 34/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II, 1942 (Box-folder 34/4)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II, 1943 - 1944 (Box-folder 34/5)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II, 1947, 1950 (Box-folder 34/6)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--POSTWAR RECONVERSION, 1945 - 1947 (Box-folder 34/7)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--SAFETY (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY-- WOMEN, 1942 - 1943 (Box-folder 34/8)
- WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--SOCIAL SERVICES (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1942 - 1944 (Box-folder 34/9)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION (See appendix for listing of U.S. Congress Hearings) See also: AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATORY WORKERS, 1942 LARC Ephemera Files, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 35/1)
- World War II--Japanese Relocation, see: WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 35/2)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 35/3)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 35/4)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION (See appendix for listing of U.S. Congress Hearings), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 36/1)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 36/2)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 36/3)
- WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 36/4)
Appendix--Pamphlet Lists
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR, 1930-1945 (Box Box 1)
  - Mexican Labor in the United States, Imperial Valley, by Paul S. Taylor, University of California Publications in Economics, V. 6, No. 1, 1928
  - Mexican Labor in the United States, Dimmit County, Winter Garden District, South Texas, by Paul S. Taylor, University of California Publications in Economics, V. 6, No. 5, 1930
  - Six Rural Problem Areas, Relief - Resources - Rehabilitation, by P. G. Beck and M. C. Forster, Federal Emergency Relief Administration, 1935
  - Agricultural Adjustment and Income, by Arthur C. Bunce, William H. Fisher, and Earle L. Rauber, Federal Reserve Bank, Postwar Economic Studies, No. 2, 1945
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATORY WORKERS, 1941 (Box Box 1, 2)
  - U. S. Congress. House. Hearings...Interstate Migration Holdings: Parts 5-10 (1941) (2 folders)
  - U. S. Congress, House. Report...Interstate Migration (1941)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATORY WORKERS Congressional Hearings (Box Box 2, 3)
  - U.S. Congress. House. Committee on Education and Labor, Hearings... Migratory Labor, 1961
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Subcommittee, Hearings... Migratory Labor, Vol. 1, 1961; Vol. 2, 1961-1962; Vol. 3, 1962
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Hearings... Amending Migratory Labor Laws, 1966.
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Hearings... Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers Powerlessness, Parts 2, 3-A, 3-B, 1966
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, Report... The Migratory Farm Labor Problem in the United States, 1966
  - U.S. Congress. House. Committee on Education and Labor, Subcommittee, Hearings... Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act Amendments of 1973, 1973
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Agriculture and Forestry, Subcommittee, Hearings...Extension of Mexican Farm Labor Program, 1961
  - U.S. Congress. House. Committee on Agriculture, Subcommittee, Hearings... Extension of Mexican Farm Labor Program, 1961
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--WPA DIVISION OF SOCIAL RESEARCH, 1937-1940 (Pamphlets listed numerically by report number) (Box Box 3, 4)
  - Areas of Intense Drought Distress, 1930-1936, Series V, Number 1, 1937
  - The People of the Drought States, Series V, Number 2, 1937
  - Relief and Rehabilitation in the Drought Area, by Irene Link, Series V, Number 3, 1937
  - The Migratory-Casual Worker, by John N. Webb, Research Monograph VII, 1937
  - Part-Time Farming in the Southeast, by R. H. Allen, L. S. Cottrell, Jr., W. W. Troxell, Harriet L. Herring, and A. D. Ewards, Research Monograph IX, 1937
  - Effects of the Works Program on Rural Relief, by Rebecca Famham and Irene Link, Research Monograph XIII, 1938
  - Changing Aspects of Rural Relief, by A. R. Mangus, Research Monograph XIV, 1938
  - Farming Hazards in the Drought Area, by R. S. Kifer and H. L. Stewart, Research Monograph XVI, 1938
  - Rural Families on Relief, by Carle C. Zimmerman and Nathan L. Whetten, Research Monograph XVII, 1039
  - Migrant Families, by John N. Webb and Malcolm Brown, Research Monograph XVIII, 1938
  - Rural Migration in the United States, by C. E. Lively and Conrad Toeuber, Research Monograph XIX, 1939
  - Youth in Agricultural Villages, by Bruce L. Melvin and Elna N. Smith, Research Monograph XXI, 1940
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1937-1939 phlets listed numerically by report number) (Box Box 4, 5)
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements in Crop Production--Sugar Beets, by Loring K. Macy, Lloyd E. Arnold, Eugene G. McKibben, and Edmund J. Stone, Report No. A-1, 1937
  - Changes in Farm Power and Equipment--Mechanical Cotton Picker, by Roman L. Horne and Eugene G. McKibben, Report No. A-2, 1937
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements in Crop Production: Potatoes, by Harry E. Knowlton, Robert B. Elwood, and Eugene G. McKibben, Report No. A-4, 1938
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements on Crop Production: C orn, by Loring K. Macy, Lloyd E. Arnold, and Eugene E. McKibben, Report No. A-5, 1938
  - Trends in Size and Production of the Aggregate Farm Enterprise, 1909-36, by Raymond G. Bressler, Jr. and John A. Hopkins, Report No. A-6, 1938
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements in Crop Production--Cotton, by William C. Holley and Lloyd E. Arnold, Report No. A-7, 1938
  - Trends in Employment in Agriculture 1909-36, by Eldon E. Shaw and John A. Hopkins, Report A-8, 1938
  - Changes in Farm Power and Equipment: Tractors, Trucks, and Automobiles, by Eugene G. McKibben and R. Austin Griffin, Report A-9, 1938
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements on Crop Production: Wheat and Oats, by Robert B. Elwood, Lloyd E. Arnold, D. Clarence Schmutz, and Eugene G. McKibben, Report No. A-10, 1939
  - Changes in Farm Power and Equipment--Field Implements, by Eugene G. McKinnen, John A. Hopkins and R. Austin Griffin, Report A-11, 1939
  - Changes in Technology and Labor Requirements on Crop Production: Vegetables, by J. C. Schilletier, Robert B. Elwood, and Harry E. Knowlton, Report No. A-12, 1939
  - Productivity and Employment in Selected Industries--Beet Sugar, by Raymond E. Adamson and Mirian E. West, Report No. N-1, 1938
- COMMITTEE FOR INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION (CIO) CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION (CIO) (Pamphlets listed by publication number, or by date of publication) (Box Box 11)
  - Industrial Unionism: The Vital Problem of Organized Labor, Publication No. 1 (undated)
  - Future of Organized Labor, by John L. Lewis, Publication No. 2 (undated)
  - Industrial Unions Mean Unity: Our Answer to President Green, Publication No. 3 (undated)
  - Case for Industrial Organization, Publication No. 4 (undated)
  - CIO What It Is ... And How It Came To Be: A Brief History of the Committee for Industrial Organization, Publication No. 12, 1937
  - Truth About CIO, Publication No. 130, (Reprint from Economic Outlook, November-December 1945)
  - CIO What It Is and What It Does, Publication No. 170 (undated)
  - "...Sugar-Coating Won't Do:" A Statement of the CIO Executive Board on the Taft- Hartley Act, 1953, Pamphlets No. 218
  - Report on Congress: The CIO Looks at the 83rd Congress, Publication No. 252, 1954
  - Maintaining Prosperity, Committee on Economic Policy, 1953
  - CIO California Council: What, Who, How, Why, 1953
- ECONOMIC SECURITY PROGRAMS, 1933-1934 (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title) (Box Box 12)
  - Economic Legislation of the Seventy-Third Congress, Volume II, National Industrial Conference Board, Inc., 1934
  - Economic Reconstruction Legislation of 1933, National Industrial Conference Board, Inc., 1933
  - Committee on Economic Security, The Need for Economic Security in United States, 1934
  - Report to the President of the Committee on Economic Security, 1935
  - Supplement to the Report to the President of the Committee on Economic Security, 1935
- EDUCATION AND LABOR EDUCATION (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by author) (Box Box 13)
  - Labor, Champion of Public Education, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Publication No. 121, (undated)
  - Federal Aid To Education: A Step Toward Real Partnership, by George Meany, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Publication No. 122 (undated)
  - Fair Taxes for Good Schools: The Case for Federal Aid, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Publication No. 123, (undated)
  - Time to Get Angry: A Counter-Offensive to the Attack on American Education, by James B. Carey, Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1953
  - Building the Local Union Education Program, by John J. Flagler, State University of Iowa, Information Series No. 4, 1961
- HEALTH INSURANCE, 1938-1970 (Pamphlets listed by dated of publication) (Box Box 13)
  - Group Purchase of Medical Care By Industrial Employees, by Leahmae Brown, Princeton University, 1938
  - What Is Management's Responsibility for the Medical Care of Its Employees? T he University of Chicago Round Table, No. 421, 1946
  - Management and Union Health Programs, 1950-1956: The Coordination of Care and Public Understanding and Acceptance of Health Services, by Leona Baumgartner and Margaret C. Klem, 1958, 1959
  - National Health Insurance: Labor's No. 1 Goal, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1970
- INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS, 1955-1973 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 14)
  - Influence of Plant Size On Industrial Relations, by Sherrill Cleland, Princeton University, 1955
  - What Organized Labor Expects of Management by George Meany: What Management Expects of Organized Labor by Charles R. Sligh, Jr., National Association of Manufacturers, 1955
  - Old Before Its Time: Collective Bargaining at 28, by Paul Jacobs, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1963
- INTERNATIONAL LABOR OFFICE 1922-1969 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 14)
  - The International Labor Organization of the League of Nations, National Industrial Conference Board, Research Report No. 48 1922
  - Lasting Peace the I.L.O. Way: The Story of the International Labour Organization, International Labour Organization 1951
  - The New World of Labor: A Panorama of the International Labor Office, American Federation of Labor, 1958
  - The United States the International Labor Organization, U.S. Dept. of Labor 1969
- LABOR FORCE U.S. BUREAU OF LABOR STATISTICS (Pamphlets listed numerically by bulletin number)1927-1942 (Box Box 14)
  - Productivity of Labor in the Glass Industry, Bulletin No. 441, 1927
  - Productivity of Labor in Merchant Blast Furnaces, Bulletin No. 474, 1929
  - Productivity of Labor in Newspaper Printing, Bulletin No. 175, 1929
  - Technological Changes and Employment in the United States Postal Service, Bulletin No. 574, 1932
  - Labor Productivity in the Automobile Tire Industry, Bulletin No. 585, by Boris Stern, 1933
  - Labor Supply in the United States: Occupational Statistics of the 1930 Census tabulated by class of work and industry, as well as by sex, race and age groups, Social Science Research Council, Committee on Social Security, 1937
- LOCAL INDEPENDENT UNIONS, 1960-1963 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 17)
  - Local Independent and National Unions: Competitive Labor Organizations, by Leo Troy, Rutgers - The State University, 1960
  - Local Independent Unionism: Two Case Studies, by Leo Troy, Rutgers - The State University, 1961
- MANUALS FOR SHOP STEWARDS, BUSINESS AGENTS, ETC., 1955-1971 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 17)
  - The Business Agent and His Union, by Wilma Rule Krauss and Van Dusen Kennedy, Institute of Industrial Relations, University of California, 1955
  - The Union Business Agent's Perspective of His Job, by Hjalmar Rosen and R. A. Hudson Rosen, University of Illinois, 1958
  - A Manual of Things Worth Knowing to Better Service Your Members, Western Conference of Teamsters, 1964
  - AFL-CIO Manual for Federal Employees, AFL-CIO Publication No. 138, 1971
  - IUE Leadership Manual for Shop Stewards, Int'l. Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, AFL-CIO (undated)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--RADIATION, 1949-1968 (Studies and pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 17)
  - Atomic Energy and the Life Sciences, U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1949
  - Radiation Disability: Will It Be Adequately Compensated? by Earl F. Cheit, Institute of Industrial Relations, University of California, 1959
  - Studies in Workmen's Compensation and Radiation Injury, Vol. I (1965) - IV (1968)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--LABOR STATEMENTS, 1947, 1973 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 17)
  - Guide to Industrial Accident Prevention Through a Joint Labor-Management Safety Committee, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1947
  - Danger: Men at Work, 1969 Occupational Safety and Health Conference of the Industrial Union Dept., AFL-CIO
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--MENTAL HEALTH, 1958, 1966 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 20)
  - The Worker's Stake in Mental Health, Community Services Committee, AFL-CIO, Publication No. 69, 1958
  - Selected Bibliography on Occupational Mental Health, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1965
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SEAMEN, 1928-1954 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 21)
  - Settlement for Accidents to American Seamen, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1928
  - Workmen's Compensation and the Protection of Seamen, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 869, 1946
  - Federal Responsibility for Medical Care of Seamen, Supporting Brief by Conference of American Maritime Unions, by C. J. Simpson, 1954
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SHIPYARD WORKERS, 1943-1977 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 21)
  - Shipyard Injuries and Their Causes, 1941, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1943
  - Minimum Requirements for Safety and Industrial Health in Contract Shipyards, U.S. Navy Dept., U.S. Maritime Commission, 1943
  - The Uncharted Seas of Shipyard Safety Health, by Harold J. Buoy, Int'l. President, Int'l. Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Ship Builders, Blacksmiths, Forgers and Helpers, AFL-CIO, 1977
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--STATISTICAL METHODS (Pamphlets listed by date of publication)1920-1944 (Box Box 21)
  - Standardization of Industrial Accident Statistics, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1920
  - Codes for Individual Accident Reports, Pennsylvania Compensation Rating and Inspection Bureau, 1922
  - Manual on Industrial-Injury Statistics, by Max D. Kossoris, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 667, 1940
  - Accident-Record Manual for Industrial Plants, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 772, 1944
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--WOMEN, 1919-1977 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 21)
  - Women in the Lead Industries, by Alice Hamilton, M.D., U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 253, 1919
  - The Employment of Women in Hazardous Industries in the United States, U.S. Dept. Of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1920
  - Industrial Accidents to Men and Women, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 81, 1930
  - Industrial Injuries to Women in 1928 and 1929 Compared With Injuries to Men, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 102, 1933
  - Industrial Injuries to Women in 1930 and 1931 Compared With Injuries to Men, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 129, 1935
  - Industrial Injuries to Women and Men, 1932 to 1934, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 160, 1938
  - The Industrial Nurse and the Woman Worker, by Jennie Mohr, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Special Bulletin No. 19, 1944
  - Industrial Injuries to Women, U.S. Dept. of Labor, Women's Bureau, Bulletin No. 212, 1947
  - The Health of Women Who Work, by Margaret F. McKiever, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1965
  - Occupational Health Problems of Pregnant Women, by Vilma R. Hunt, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975
  - Guidelines on Pregnancy and Work, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1977
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--YOUNG WORKERS, 1951-1966 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 21)
  - Hazardous Employments Prohibited to Minors Sixteen and Over by State and Federal Laws and Rulings, State of New York, Dept. of Labor, 1951
  - Hazardous Employment Prohibited for Minors Under State Child-Labor Laws, U.S. Bureau of Labor Standards, Bulletin 205, 1959
  - We're Never Too Young to Learn Safety, U.S. Bureau of Labor Standards, 1959
  - The Challenge to Supervisors...Making Young Workers Safe Workers, U.S. Bureau of Labor Standards, 1966
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--YOUNG WORKERS U.S. DEPT. OF LABOR, CHILDREN'S BUREAU AND BUREAU OF LABOR STANDARDS, 1941-1966 (Box Box 21)
  - Occupational Hazards to Young Workers, Reports Nos. 1-18
    - Report No. 1. - The Explosives Manufacturing Industries, 1942
    - Report No. 2. - Motor-Vehicle Drivers and Helpers, 1941
    - Report No. 3. - The Coal-Mining Industry, 1942
    - Report No. 4. - The Logging and Sawmilling Industries, 1942
    - Report No. 4-A- Supplementary Investigation of the Sawmilling Industry, 1942
    - Report No. 5. -Woodworking Machines, 1942
    - Report No. 6. - Radioactive Substances, 1942
    - Report No. 7. - The Operation of Housing Apparatus, 1946
    - Report No. 8. - The Operation of Power-Driven, Metal-Forming, Punching, and Shearing Machines, 1950
    - Report No. 9. - Mining Other Than Coal, 195 1
    - Report No. 10 - Slaughtering, Meat-Packing and Rendering, 1952
    - Report No. 11 - Hazards of Operating Bakery Machines, 1952
    - Report No. 12 - The Operation of Paper-Products Machines, 1955
    - Report No. 13 - The Manufacture of Brick, Tile, and Kindred Products, 1956
    - Report No. 16 - Roofing Operations, 1962
    - Report No. 17 - Excavation Operations, 1963
    - Report No. 18 - Highway and Street Construction Operations (Preliminary Draft), 1966
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT, 1916-1980 (Pamphlets listed by date of publication) (Box Box 23)
  - Unemployment in the United States, U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1916
  - Employment in Selected Manufacturing Industries, U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1928
  - Unions Provide Against Unemployment, American Federation of Labor, 1929. 109 p.
  - Trade Unions Study Unemployment, American Federation of Labor, 1929
  - U. S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Education and Labor...Hearings, Unemployment in the United States, 1929
  - "Dependability and Meaning of Unemployment and Employment Statistics in the United States, " by Royal Miiker, Harvard Business Review, July, 1930
  - Unemployment and Adult Education...a Symposium.... M orse A. Cartwright, editor, American Association for Adult Education, 1931. 63 p.
  - U. S. Bureau of the Census, United States Summary Unemployment, 1931
  - The United States Employment Service, by Ruth M. Kellogg, University of Chicago Press, 1933
  - Revised Indexes of Factory Employment and Pay Rolls, 1919 to 1933, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 610, by Lewis E. Talbert and Alice Glenin, 1935
  - Who are the Job Seekers? U.S. Department of Labor, United States Employment Service, 1937
  - Final Report on Total and Partial Unemployment: United States Summary with Data for Geographical Divisions, Cities, and States, 1938
  - Survey of Employment Service Information, February 1938, May 1939
  - "Controversial Aspects of Unemployment Statistics in the United States," The Review of Economic Statistics, May 1941
  - Full Employment Patterns, 1950, U. S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1947
  - Income, Education, and Unemployment in Neighborhoods, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1963
  - Economic Dislocation: Plant Closings, Plant Relocations and Pland Conversion, Joint Report of Labor Union Study Tour Participants, 1979
  - Groups with Historically High Incidences of Unemployment, U.S. Department of Labor, Employment Standards Administration, 1980
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical), 1935 (Box Box 24)
  - Classified Reports of Placements, May 1935 - March 1938, California State Employment Service. (5 folders)
  - Monthly Operation Reports of the U. S. Employment Service ( for California)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS, 1929-1935 (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title) (Box Box 25)
  - Effect of the Economic Depression on Jewish Social Work, 1931
  - U. S., Bureau of the Census, Relief Expenditures by Governmental and Private Organizations, 1929 and 1931, 1932
  - Setting Up a Program of Work Relief, by Joanna C. Colcord, 1931
  - U.S. Congress. Senate. Committee on Manufactures. Subcommittee...Hearings, 1933. Holdings:
  - Federal Aid for Unemployment Relief Relief for Unemployed Transients Unemployment Relief
  - U. S. Department of Commerce, State Legislation for Unemployment Relief, 1931 and 1932
  - U. S. Department of Labor, Trends in Different Types of Public and Private Relief in Urban Areas, 1929-35, 1937
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT 1939-1940 (Box Box 26)
  - Mineral Technology and Output Per Man Studies: Rock Drilling, by C. E. Nighman and O. E. Kiessling, Report No. E-11, 1940
  - Labor Productivity in the Boot and Shoe Industry, by Boris Stern, Report No. B-6, 1939
  - Effects of Technological Developments Upon Capital Formation, by David Weintraub, Report No. G-4, 1939
  - Industrial Instruments and Changing Technology, by George Perazich, Herbert Schimmel and Benjamin Rosenberg, Report No. M-1, 1938
  - Productivity and Employment in Selected Industries: Brick and Tile, by Miriam E. West, Report No. N-2, 1939
  - Production, Employment, and Productivity in 59 Manufacturing Industries, 1919-36: Part One: Purpose, Methods and Summary of Findings, by Harry Magdoff, Irving H. Siegel, and Milton B. Davis, Report No. S-1, 1939
  - ----: Part Two: Indexes for Individual Industries and Methods of Construction, Report No. S-1, Part Two, 1939
  - ----: Part Three: Appendexes, Report No. S-1, Part Three, 1939
  - National Research Project on Re-Employment Opportunities and Recent Changes in Industrial Techniques: Summary of Findings to Date, March 1938, by David Weintraub and Irving Kaplan, 1938
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE, 1922-1935 (Pamphlets listed by publication date) (Box Box 27)
  - Princeton University, Industrial Relations Section, Company Plans for Unemployment Benefits, 1931
  - The Reference Shelf, Compulsory Unemployment Insurance, 1931
  - Current Conflicting Views on Unemployment Insurance, by T. H. Hall, 1931
  - "Dole Versus Unemployment Insurance," by George R. Mangold, S ociology and Social Research, January-February 1932
  - Employment Assurance and Insurance, by Gerard Swope, President, General Electric Company, 1932
  - "Fundamental Faults of Compulsory Public Unemployment Insurance," American Industries, December 1932, Official Publication of the National Association of Manufactures
  - "Insurance as a Factor in the Solution of the Problems That Follow Depression," Address by Honorable Felix Hebert, U. S. Senator from Rhode Island